Guide to the South African Apartheid Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Non-Parliamentary/Opposition/Pressure Groups, 1961-1991; Series III
  - South Africa: The Agony of a Black Radical by Themba Sono, pp. 1-282, 1970-1974 (Box 15, Folder 213 - 214)
  - South Africa: The Agony of a Black Radical, pp. 283-370, 1970-1974 (Box 16, Folder 215)
  - Soweto Student's Congress (SOSCO), undated (Box 16, Folder 216)
  - SSM Movement, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 217)
  - Steel and Engineering Industries Federation of South Africa (SEIFSA), 1987 (Box 16, Folder 218)
  - Student Moderate Alliance, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 219)
  - Studente vir n' Democratiese Samalewing (SDS), undated (Box 16, Folder 220)
  - Students Christian Association, 1982-1983 (Box 16, Folder 221)
  - Students of Young Azania (SOYA), undated (Box 16, Folder 222)
  - Students Revolutionary Front, undated (Box 16, Folder 223)
  - Sweet, Food and Allied Worker's Union (SFAWU), 1984 (Box 16, Folder 224)
  - Tembisa Youth Congress (TEYCO), undated (Box 16, Folder 225)
  - Thornhill Youth Congress, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 226)
  - Traditional Family Property- Bureau for Southern Africa (TFP), 1988 (Box 16, Folder 227)
  - Transvaal Indian Congress (TIC), 1983-1988 (Box 16, Folder 228)
  - Transvaal Rural Action Committee (TRAC), 1984-1989 (Box 16, Folder 229)
  - UNB, undated (Box 16, Folder 230)
  - Union of Black Journalists (UBJ), 1976 (Box 16, Folder 231)
  - United Democratic Front (UDF)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 16, Folder 232)
    - 1984-1989 (Box 16, Folder 233)
  - United Women's Congress (UWC), 1988-1989 (Box 16, Folder 234)
  - United Women's Organisation (UWO), undated (Box 16, Folder 235)
  - University of Cape Town
    - 1974-1982 (Box 16, Folder 236)
    - 1982-1990 (Box 17, Folder 237)
  - University of Cape Town Workers' Committee, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 238)
  - University of Durban-Westville, undated (Box 17, Folder 239)
  - University of Natal, 1985-1986 (Box 17, Folder 240)
  - University of Stellenbosch, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 241)
  - University of Western Cape, undated (Box 17, Folder 242)
  - University of Witwatersrand
    - 1975 (Box 17, Folder 243)
    - 1975-1991 (Box 17, Folder 244)
  - University of Zululand, undated (Box 17, Folder 245)
  - Urban Training Project, 1973-1975 (Box 17, Folder 246)
  - U.W.T.E.C., 1985 (Box 17, Folder 247)
  - Veterans for Victory, undated (Box 17, Folder 248)
  - Voice of the Martyrs, undated (Box 17, Folder 249)
  - Wages Commission, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 250)
  - "We in South Africa", undated (Box 17, Folder 251)
  - Western Cape Conscientious Objector Group, 1983-1984 (Box 17, Folder 252)
  - Western Cape Schools, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 253)
  - Western Cape Students Congress (WESCO), undated (Box 17, Folder 254)
  - Western Cape Students Council, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 255)
  - Western Cape Teachers Union (WECTU), 1985-1988 (Box 17, Folder 256)
  - Western Cape Youth League, undated (Box 17, Folder 257)
  - Western Province Council of Churches, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 258)
  - Western Province Senior Schools' Sports Union (WPSSSU), 1985 (Box 18, Folder 259)
  - White Liberation Movement of South Africa (BBB), undated (Box 18, Folder 260)
  - Women's Legal Status Committee, 1976-1979 (Box 18, Folder 261)
  - Yusuf Dadoo Memorial Committee, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 262)
  - Photographs of children and youth tortured by South African police members, 1987-1988 (Box 18, Folder 262a)
- South African Institutes and Foundations, 1966-1991; Series IV
  Series IV includes material of research institutions and foundations that function in South Africa. Files in this series are arranged alphabetically while documents within each folder are arranged chronologically.
  - Africa Institute of South Africa, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 263)
  - Association for Rural Advancement, 1986-1991 (Box 19, Folder 264)
  - Cape of Good Hope Foundation, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 265)
  - Centre for African Studies, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 266)
  - Club SA Action Research, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 267)
  - Economic Research Committee, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 268)
  - Federation of Women's Institutes, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 269)
  - Get Ahead Foundation, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 270)
  - Human Sciences Research Council (HSRC), 1986 (Box 19, Folder 271)
  - Institute for Black Research, 1983-1985 (Box 19, Folder 272)
  - Institute for Strategic Studies, undated (Box 19, Folder 273)
  - Institute of Personnel Management, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 274)
  - Labour Research Service, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 275)
  - Longreach Services, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 276)
  - Prescon Business News Agency, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 277)
  - Roland Host Association, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 278)
  - (1820) Settlers National Monument Foundation, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 279)
  - Signatory Association, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 280)
  - South African Committee for Higher Education (SACHED), undated (Box 19, Folder 281)
  - South African Foundation, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 282)
  - South African Institute of International Affairs, 1966-1980 (Box 19, Folder 283)
  - South African Institute of Race Relations (SAIRR), 1964-1991 (Box 19, Folder 284)
  - South African Outlook, 1970-1975 (Box 19, Folder 285)
  - South African Forum, 1980-1983 (Box 19, Folder 286)
  - Southern African Labour and Development Research Unit, 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 287)
  - Southern Africa Report Association, undated (Box 19, Folder 288)
  - Southern Africa Research Service, 1982-1989 (Box 19, Folder 289)
  - Southern African Editorial Services, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 290)
  - Southern African News Agency, 1963-1971 (Box 19, Folder 291)
  - Terrorism Research Associates, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 292)
  - Urban Foundation, 1977-1986 (Box 19, Folder 293)
- American Government Policy Towards South Africa, 1974-1988; Series V
  Series V documents American policy and action towards South Africa. Files in this series are arranged alphabetically with documents within each folder arranged chronologically.
  - American Consulate/Embassy, 1974-1990 (Box 20, Folder 294)
  - Congress of the United States, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 295)
  - Department of Labor, undated (Box 20, Folder 296)
  - Senate of the United States, undated (Box 20, Folder 297)
  - United States Information Services, 1977-1984 (Box 20, Folder 298)
- Disinvestment/Divestment, 1978-1987; Series VI
  Materials in this series focus on the disinvestment and divestment issues and their effectiveness as strategies for change. Files are arranged alphabetically with documents within each folder arranged chronologically.
  - African Index, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 299)
  - American Chamber of Commerce, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 300)
  - American Library Association, undated (Box 21, Folder 301)
  - Bank America Corporation, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 302)
  - Barlow Rand Limited (South Africa), 1981 (Box 21, Folder 303)
  - Chamber of Mines (South Africa), 1982-1986 (Box 21, Folder 304)
  - Coalition for Illinois Divestment from South Africa (CIDSA), 1983-1985 (Box 21, Folder 305)
  - Columbia University
    - 1978-1985 (Box 21, Folder 306)
    - 1983-1986 (Box 21, Folder 307)
    - 1985 (Box 21, Folder 308)
  - Gottlieb, Michael [Yale senior], undated (Box 21, Folder 309)
  - Harvard University, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 310)
  - Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility (ICCR), 1986 (Box 21, Folder 311)
  - Investor Responsibility Research Center (IRRC)
    - 1984-1986 (Box 21, Folder 312)
    - 1986 (Box 22, Folder 313)
  - McAlvany Intelligence Advisor, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 314)
  - Mobil Corporation, 1986-1987 (Box 22, Folder 315)
  - Northwestern University, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 316)
  - South African Manpower Review (South Africa), 1985 (Box 22, Folder 317)
  - Stanford University
    - 1985 (Box 22, Folder 318)
    - 1985-1988 (Box 22, Folder 319)
    - 1983-1987 [clippings] (Box 22, Folder 320)
  - TIAA-CREF Divestment Campaign, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 321)
  - University of California [clippings], 1982-1985 (Box 23, Folder 322)
  - University of Illinois, undated (Box 23, Folder 323)
  - Washington- Johannesburg Letter, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 324)
  - Yale University
    - 1978-1985 (Box 23, Folder 325)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 23, Folder 326)
- American Anti-Apartheid Pressure Groups, 1972-1991; Series VII
  Series VII documents the role of numerous American groups in removing racial oppression in South Africa. Files in this series are arranged alphabetically with documents within each folder arranged chronologically.
  - African Fund
    - 1976-1988 (Box 24, Folder 327)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 24, Folder 328)
    - 1991 (Box 24, Folder 329)
  - African-American Institute (Saspost)
    - 1972-1974 (Box 24, Folder 330)
    - 1975-1991 (Box 24, Folder 331)
  - African American Scholar's Council, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 332)
  - African Progressive Study Group, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 333)
  - Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 334)
  - American Broadcasting Companies (ABC), 1990 (Box 24, Folder 335)
  - American Committee on Africa
    - 1960-1984 (Box 24, Folder 336)
    - 1985-1991 (Box 25, Folder 337)
  - American Federation of Labor (AFL-CIO), 1990 (Box 25, Folder 338)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1981-1990 (Box 25, Folder 339)
  - American Labor Education Center, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 340)
  - American Library Association, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 341)
  - Americans Concerned about South Africa, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 342)
  - Amnesty International (USA), 1986-1991 (Box 25, Folder 343)
  - Anti-Apartheid Action Sheet, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 344)
  - Association of Concerned African Scholars, 1986-1989 (Box 25, Folder 345)
  - Bishop Tutu Refugee Fund, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 346)
  - Boney-Luthuli Defense Fund, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 347)
  - Campaign to Oppose Bank Loans to South Africa (COBLSA), 1982 (Box 25, Folder 348)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 349)
  - Clergy and Laity Concerned, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 350)
  - Coalition to Defend Albany, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 351)
  - Coke Campaign, 1987-1989 (Box 25, Folder 352)
  - Columbia University, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 353)
  - Commission on Social Action of Reform Judaism, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 354)
  - Committee for a Free Mozambique, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 355)
  - Committee for Health in Southern Africa (CHISA), 1984-1986 (Box 25, Folder 356)
  - Episcopal Churchpeople for a Free Southern Africa
    - 1976-1987 (Box 26, Folder 357)
    - 1988-1991 (Box 26, Folder 358)
    - 1991 (Box 26, Folder 359)
  - Feminist International for Peace and Food (FIPF), 1985-1986 (Box 26, Folder 360)
  - Food First Books, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 361)
  - Grassroots International, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 362)
  - Heritage Foundation, 1982-1986 (Box 26, Folder 363)
  - Illinois Anti-Apartheid Groups, 1985-1986 (Box 26, Folder 364)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs, 1982-1985 (Box 26, Folder 365)
  - Institute of Human Rights, undated (Box 26, Folder 366)
  - International Council for Equality of Opportunity Principles, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 367)
  - International Defense and Aid Fund (IDAF), 1982-1986 (Box 26, Folder 368)
  - Intro-Communications, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 369)
  - Labor Black League for Social Defense, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 370)
  - Lawyer's Committee for Civil Rights, 1982-1987 (Box 26, Folder 371)
  - Mozambique Support Network, 1988-1989 (Box 26, Folder 372)
  - National Namibia Concerns, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 373)
  - New Haven Anti-Apartheid Groups, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 374)
  - Newsclippings, 1988-1991 (Box 27, Folder 375)
  - New York Anti-Apartheid Coalition, undated (Box 27, Folder 376)
  - New York Anti-Apartheid Co-ordinating Council, 1986-1988 (Box 27, Folder 377)
  - New York Mobilization for Justice and Peace in Central America and Southern Africa, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 378)
  - November 29thCommittee for Palestine, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 379)
  - Ohio University, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 380)
  - Oxfam America, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 381)
  - Peregrine Media Group, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 382)
  - Ralph Bunche Institute, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 383)
  - Restore a More Benevolent Order Coalition (RAMBOC), 1988 (Box 27, Folder 384)
  - Revolutionary Communist Party, 1981-1988 (Box 27, Folder 385)
  - Riverside Church Disarmament Program, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 386)
  - San Francisco State University, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 387)
  - South African Freedom Fund, undated (Box 27, Folder 388)
  - Southern Africa Committee, undated (Box 27, Folder 389)
  - Southern Africa Media Center, undated (Box 27, Folder 390)
  - Southern Africa Research Association, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 391)
  - Students for a Free South Africa, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 392)
  - Transafrica, 1985-1990 (Box 27, Folder 393)
  - Union of American Hebrew Congregations, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 394)
  - United Mineworkers of America, undated (Box 27, Folder 395)
  - United Nations, 1982-1987 (Box 27, Folder 396)
  - University of California (UCLA), 1984 (Box 27, Folder 397)
  - Washington Office on Africa
    - 1973-1987 (Box 27, Folder 398)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 27, Folder 399)
  - West Indian-American Calypso Association (WIACA), 1986 (Box 27, Folder 400)
  - Western States Mobilization for Peace, Jobs and Justice, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 401)
  - Worldview Forum, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 402)
  - Worldwide Church of God, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 403)
- International Pressure Groups, 1963-1991; Series VIII
  Series VIII focuses on the role of non-American groups and their respective governments to bring an end to apartheid. Files are arranged alphabetically with documents within each folder arranged chronologically.
  - African Caribbean Self Help Organisation (Birmingham, England), 1989 (Box 28, Folder 404)
  - African Liberation Committee, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 405)
  - Afrika-Centrum (Amsterdam), 1963 (Box 28, Folder 406)
  - Afrikagrupperna (Africa Group of Sweden), 1985-1987 (Box 28, Folder 407)
  - Anti-Apartheid Bewegung (Berlin), 1987 (Box 28, Folder 408)
  - Anti-Apartheid Movement (London), 1981-1984 (Box 28, Folder 409)
  - Anti-Apartheid Movement
    - 1984-1988 (Box 28, Folder 410)
    - 1989-1991 (Box 28, Folder 411)
  - Association of South African Students (London), undated (Box 28, Folder 412)
  - Awa-Finnaba (Berlin), 1988 (Box 28, Folder 413)
  - Azania Struggle (Wellington, New Zealand), 1983 (Box 28, Folder 414)
  - Bishop Ambrose Reeves Trust (BART) (London), undated (Box 28, Folder 415)
  - British Defence and Aid Fund for Southern Africa (London), 1989-1991 (Box 28, Folder 416)
  - British Theatre, undated (Box 28, Folder 417)
  - Campaign Against Racial Exploitation (Australia), 1989 (Box 29, Folder 418)
  - Catholic Institute for International Affairs (CIIA) (London), 1983-1990 (Box 29, Folder 419)
  - Centro de Estudos Africanos (Mozambique), 1979-1990 (Box 29, Folder 420)
  - Christian Concern for Southern Africa (CSSA) (London), 1986 (Box 29, Folder 421)
  - Christians Against Racism and Fascism (London), 1985 (Box 29, Folder 422)
  - Committee on Southern African War Resistance (COSAWR) (London), 1986-1990 (Box 29, Folder 423)
  - Commonwealth Secretariat (London), 1985-1986 (Box 29, Folder 424)
  - Development Education Centre (Birmingham, England), 1989 (Box 29, Folder 425)
  - End Loans to South Africa (ELTSA) (London), 1983-1991 (Box 29, Folder 426)
  - European Campaign Against South African Aggression on Mozambique and Angola (ECASAAMA), undated (Box 29, Folder 427)
  - European Economic Community (EEC), 1984 (Box 29, Folder 428)
  - Fires (London), 1986 (Box 29, Folder 429)
  - Front line Worker (London), 1989 (Box 29, Folder 430)
  - Health and Refugee Trust of South Africa (HEART), London, undated (Box 29, Folder 431)
  - Holland Committee on Southern Africa (Amsterdam), 1983 (Box 29, Folder 432)
  - International Campaign Against Apartheid Sport (London), 1986-1990 (Box 29, Folder 433)
  - International Campaign Against Banking on Apartheid (ICABA) (London), 1989-1991 (Box 29, Folder 434)
  - International Committee Against Apartheid, Racism and Colonialism in Southern Africa (London), 1979 (Box 29, Folder 435)
  - International Committee of the Red Cross (Geneva), 1986 (Box 29, Folder 436)
  - International Defense and Aid Fund for Southern Africa (IDAF) (London), 1972-1988 (Box 29, Folder 437)
  - International Society for Human Rights (ISHR) (London), 1989 (Box 29, Folder 438)
  - International University Exchange Fund (Geneva), 1974-1978 (Box 29, Folder 439)
  - Irish Anti-Apartheid Movement (Dublin), 1987-1991 (Box 30, Folder 440)
  - Isolate South Africa Committee (Sweden), 1985-1987 (Box 30, Folder 441)
  - Isivivane (Berlin), 1990 (Box 30, Folder 442)
  - Joint Campaign Against the Repression of Trade Unionists in South Africa and Namibia (London), undated (Box 30, Folder 443)
  - Labour Party (Britain), 1985 (Box 30, Folder 444)
  - L'Afrique du Sud (Paris), 1990-1991 (Box 30, Folder 445)
  - Lawyers Against Apartheid (London), 1986-1991 (Box 30, Folder 446)
  - Local Authority (London), 1985-1988 (Box 30, Folder 447)
  - Mouvement Anti-Apartheid de Suisse (MAAS) (Geneva), 1978 (Box 30, Folder 448)
  - National and Local Government Officers Association (NALGO) (London), 1987 (Box 30, Folder 449)
  - Non-Governmental Organisations on Human Rights (Geneva), 1976-1984 (Box 30, Folder 450)
  - Nordic Countries, undated (Box 30, Folder 451)
  - Northwest Trade Union Anti-Apartheid Liaison Committee (Manchester), 1983 (Box 30, Folder 452)
  - Organisation of African Unity (OAU) (Ethiopia), 1968-1978 (Box 30, Folder 453)
  - Oxfam (Oxford), 1986-1990 (Box 30, Folder 454)
  - Parti-Communiste Révolutionnaire des Etats Unis (London), 1985 (Box 30, Folder 455)
  - Royal Commonwealth Society (London), undated (Box 30, Folder 456)
  - Sampson Letter (London), 1986 (Box 30, Folder 457)
  - Society for the Propagation of the Gospel (London), 1985 (Box 30, Folder 458)
  - South African Cultural Workers Association (London), undated (Box 30, Folder 459)
  - South African Labour and Education Project (SALEP) (London), 1982 (Box 30, Folder 460)
  - South African Non-Racial Olympic Committee (London), 1985-1986 (Box 30, Folder 461)
  - Southern African Development Co-Ordination Conference (SADCC) (Botswana), 1980 (Box 30, Folder 462)
  - Stop War Against Angola and Mozambique (SWAM) (London), undated (Box 30, Folder 463)
  - Sudliches Afrika (Bonn), 1976 (Box 30, Folder 464)
  - SWAPO Foreign Mission (Cairo), 1963 (Box 30, Folder 465)
  - Swedish Government, undated (Box 30, Folder 466)
  - UN Association of Sweden, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 467)
  - World Campaign Against Military and Nuclear Collaboration with South Africa, 1983-1984 (Box 30, Folder 468)
  - World Federation of Democractic Youth (Budapest), 1983 (Box 30, Folder 469)
  - World Gold Commission (WGC) (London), undated (Box 30, Folder 470)
  - World University Service (WUS) (London), 1987 (Box 30, Folder 471)
  - Youth Forum of European Communities (Belgium), undated (Box 30, Folder 472)
  - Zuid Afrikaansche Stichsting Moederland te Amsterdam (Amsterdam), 1989 (Box 30, Folder 473)
- Posters and Printed Materials, 1968-1991; Series IX
  This series consists of oversized printed materials.
  - Posters, 1985-1991 (Folder 31A–31C)
  - Posters, 1985-1991 (Box 32)
  - Printed material including scattered issues of serials, 1968-1990 (Box 33)
  - Printed material including scattered issues of serials, 1968-1990 (Box 34)
- Additional Material, 1961-1991 (inclusive), 1990-1991 (bulk); Accession 1995-M-101
  - South African government
    - Bureau for Information, [1988?] (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Department of Constitutional Development and Planning, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Department of Information, [1976?] (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "National Peace Accord", 1991 September 14 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - South African Defence Force (SADF), [1982?], 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - South African Embassy, London, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Toespraak Van Sy Edele M. C. Botha, L. V., Minister Van Bantoe-Administrasie En-Ont-Wikkeling En Van Bantoe-Onder-Wys By Geleentheid Van Die Opening", 1969 August (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) [in conjunction with the government of the Republic of South Africa], 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - South African parliamentary parties
    - Democratic Party, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Progressive Party, [1961?], 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Unity Party, [1969], 1971-1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Non-parliamentary/opposition/pressure groups
    - African National Congress
      - 1978, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - 1991 Feb 5-8 [Donors Conference, Arusha] (Box 1, Folder 15 - 16)
      - 1991 May-Jun (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - 1991 Jul 2-7 [National Conference, Durban] (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - 1991 Jul 16-28, Aug 9 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - 1991 Oct (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - 1991 Nov 1-15 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - 1991 Nov 20-29 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - 1991 Dec 1-9 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - 1991 Dec 10-16 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - 1991 Dec 17-30 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Umkhonto we Sizwe, 1986, [1991] (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Aida Parker Newsletter (APN), 1985 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Anti-Censorship Action Group, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Azanian People's Organization (AZAPO), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Black Sash, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Cape Action League (CAL), [1987?] (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Cape Teachers' Professional Association (C.T.P.A.), 1977 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Community Agency for Social Enquiry (CASE), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Congress of South African Writers (COSAW), [1987?]-1989 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Conscientious Objector Support Group (COSG), 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 35 - 36)
    - Human Awareness Programme, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Inkatha, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - International Socialists of South Africa (ISSA), 1991 September-October (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Merit Party, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Mowbray Youth Congress, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Natal Indian Congress, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - National Union of Metalworkers of South Africa (NUMSA), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - New Unity Movement, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Pan Africanist Congress (PAC), 1980 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - South African Bureau of Racial Affairs (SABRA), 1990 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - South African Clothing and Textile Workers Union (SACTWU), 1991 November (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - South African Communist Party (SACP)
      - [1987?], 1991 Feb-Jul (Box 3, Folder 48)
      - 1991 Sep, Nov, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - South African Indian Council (SAIC), undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - South African Pressclips [series of topical newspaper clippings collected in brochure form]
      - "Apartheid Dead? FW's Speech, Reaction and Comment", 1991 February (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - "Congresses, Conferences, and Position Statements in 1990", 1991 January (Box 3, Folder 52)
      - "Death Squads", 1990 (Box 3, Folder 53)
      - "The Hunger Strike, 1 May 1991 to 16 June 1991", 1991 June (Box 3, Folder 54)
      - "PAC Unbanned", 1990 September (Box 3, Folder 55)
      - "SACP Unbanned", 1990 August (Box 3, Folder 56)
      - "South Africa's Intelligence Services", 1991 May (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - South African Students Press Union, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Transvaal Indian Congress
      - 1962 (Box 4, Folder 59)
      - 1963-1967 (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - n.d. (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Transvaal Indian Youth Congress
      - 1961 (Box 4, Folder 62)
      - 1962-1964, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - University of Bophuthatswana, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - University of Cape Town, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - University of Durban-Westville, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - University of Natal, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - University of the Western Cape, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 68)